mypersonalfinancejourney.com 2015-09-06

# Privacy Policy and Disclaimer — My Personal Finance Journey

**Privacy Policy for  <http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/>**

The privacy of our visitors to [mypersonalfinancejourney.com](http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/) is important to us.

At [mypersonalfinancejourney.com](http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/), we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit [mypersonalfinancejourney.com](http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/), and how we safeguard your information. We never sell your personal information to third parties.

Log Files – As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

Cookies and Web Beacons – We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site. This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on [mypersonalfinancejourney.com](http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/) to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

DoubleClick DART cookies – We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses “non personally identifiable information”. It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites. This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

Kontera Double Underlined Ads – These links are part of a pay per click advertising program called Kontera. Kontera is an In Text advertising service: they take my text and create links within it. If you hover with your mouse over these double underlined links, you will see a small dialog box containing advertisement related to the text marked. You can choose to either move the mouse away and go on with your browsing, or to press on the box and go to the ad page which is relevant to the text. [Click here to learn more about Kontera Double Underline Link Ads](http://www.kontera.com/about-us).

RSS Subscriptions – This website records information about how people access our RSS feeds, but does not collect any personally identifying information from or about our RSS subscribers.

Collection of non-personally-identifiable information by third parties – Third parties (including advertising services) may be placing and reading cookies on your browser in the normal course of providing services to this website. Some services on this site also may use web beacons (tiny small transparent images) to collect information in the course of providing services to this website. Your web browser should have options to manage cookies should this be desirable. Consult your browser’s help section for information on viewing, setting, and changing these options. We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information ( _not_  including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

E-mail Subscriptions – This website’s feed services collect the e-mail addresses of individuals that subscribe to our RSS feed via e-mail. Individual information about subscribers to this website’s feed is held in strict confidence; we will not release or disclose any specific subscriber information under any circumstances, unless required by law. Aggregated information stripped of any personally identifiable information may be disclosed.

Web Server Traffic – This website records information about how people access this website. This includes things such as your IP address (or DNS), your browser, and your operating system. We do not and will not use this information to track down any personally identifiable information about you, unless required by law.

Comments – Comments submitted to this website are the responsibility of the commenter. We reserve the right to remove or edit comments at our discretion. Site URLs (if provided) are published along with comments. E-mail addresses are required with the submission of comments but are not disclosed, unless the commenter deliberately does so him/herself by entering the e-mail address in the main comment box in addition to the box clearly labeled for the e-mail address.

E-mail – E-mail sent to the site either through the contact form or directly to the owner in connection with this site is considered property of this site, and questions or tips may be published at the owner’s option. In such cases, this website will not disclose any personally identifying information, unless required to by law.

External Links – The web site contains links to other websites not owned by the owner of this website. We will not, and cannot, control how your personal information is used on these other websites. Consult the privacy policies of the linked websites to see how they use your information.

**Disclaimer for  <http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/>**

The information contained within MyPersonalFinanceJourney.com is for general information and does not constitute professional financial advice. The contents represent individual opinions (although, they are usually well-informed and logical). Any information you use from this site is used entirely at your own risk, and the site owners and operators specifically disclaim all warranties, express, implied or statutory, regarding the accuracy, timeliness, and/or completeness of the information contained herein, as well as its suitability to any particular need. Please [contact us](http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/p/contact-me.html) directly to schedule a consultation if you require advice regarding your specific situation.

**Disclosure Policy for  <http://www.mypersonalfinancejourney.com/>**

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. For questions about this blog, please contact  [Jacob@mypersonalfinancejourney.com](mailto:Jacob@mypersonalfinancejourney.com).

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, paid insertions, affiliate programs, or other forms of compensation.

The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post may not always be identified as paid or sponsored content.

The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

To get your own policy, go to http://www.disclosurepolicy.org

Thanks for visiting our site!
